<course name="JS/CSS Course">
    <unit name="Intro">
     <section>
            <title>Introduction to CSS/JS</title>
            <content>In additional to HTML, there are two other software technologies that are at the core of web development. These are CSS and JavaScript.</content>
            <content>CSS, also called Cascading Style Sheets is not a true programming language, but also a markup language that is similiar to HTML. However, instead of defining how a 
            webpage is laid out, CSS defines how a webpage looks.</content>
            <content>
                JavaScript is the other topic covered in this unit, and it is indeed a full-fledged programming language. JS runs on the client side, and is used to modify a sites behaviour.
                JS is used for a variety of functions, and is also responsible for sending requests to other websites from a webpage. These requests can do anything from fetch data, to 
                communicating with a backend server.
            </content>
        </section>
    </unit>
    <unit name="CSS">
        <section>
            <title>CSS</title>
            <content>
                CSS files contain items called <i>selectors</i> which apply a style to an element on the page. There are a vareity of ways to select an element on a page.
                Most commonly, CSS selectors will select based on either the classname or the id of an element. A classname offers a more broad selection, meaning multiple styles can be applied
                to the same element. A selection based on an id will only affect the element with that id.
            </content>
        </section>
    </unit>
    <unit name="JS">
        <section>
            <title>JavaScript Basics</title>
            <content>
                JS is a client-side scripting language that has become the backbone of modern web development. 
                Developed in the late nineties, JS has evolved over the years to serve a number of functions.
                Some basic knowledge of programming is assumed for this next section.
            </content>
            <content>Javascript can be directly added to a webpage by using the &lt;script&gt;&lt;/script&gt; tag. Inside this Html tag, any type of JavaScript can be written.</content>
            <content>JavaScript supports variables, loops, strings just like any normal programming langauge.</content>
            <content>In JS, the console.log method is used to print to the console (found in the inspection tools in most browsers). JavaScript also supports two types of equality checking.</content>
            <content>Double equal signs are used to compare the values of two variables, and triple equals compares the type and value.</content>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>JavaScript and the DOM</title>
            <content>
                The DOM is crucial for performing page interactions with JavaScript. The DOM (Document Object Model) is a representation of the html on a page.
                It can be used to interact with elements, add event listeners, and a host more options.
            </content>
            <content>
                When embedded in a page, JS has access to the <i>document</i> object. The querySelector method can be used to select elements (using a style familiar to our CSS selectors).
                For example, the code below selects all elements with the .sublink class, and adds an event listener which, when the element is clicked, will call two functions, fetchPage and
                setActiveLink
            </content>
            <content>
                Event listeners are crucial for performing interactions with a webpage during runtime. The click event will call what is known as a callback function that is run when the
                element experiences a click event.
            </content>
        </section>
    </unit>
    <quiz name="JS/CSS Quiz">
        <question question="What are the two additional software technologies use to develop websites?" answer="a">
            <option option="a">Html and CSS</option>
            <option option="b">Go and Microservices</option>
            <option option="c">C++ and IDEs</option>
        </question>
         <question question="What is the CSS selector which adds extra space outside the element?" answer="b">
            <option option="a">Padding</option>
            <option option="b">Margin</option>
            <option option="c">Background</option>
        </question>
         <question question="How would you select all elements with the class 'myElement' in CSS?" answer="c">
            <option option="a">myElement</option>
            <option option="b">#myElement</option>
            <option option="c">.myElement</option>
        </question>
         <question question="What is the difference between the double and triple equal signs in JS?" answer="c">
            <option option="a">Double equal signs are used to compare the values of two variables, and triple equals compares the type and value.</option>
            <option option="b">Nothing.</option>
            <option option="c">Triple equal signs are used to compare the values of two variables, and double equals compares the type and value.</option>
        </question>
    </quiz>
</course>